Finding Aid for the Hugo Ballin Papers LSC.0407
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Literary Manuscripts (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4, Box 5, Box 6, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12, Box 13)
  - The Strange Case of Dr. Blake, by X.Y.Z., Typescript with corrections. 278pp. In black, spring binder. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Chapter 1 is titled "The Damned Dr. Blake".
  - And They Hang Pictures., Typescript with holograph corrections. Original and only copy. 261pp. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - How Many Hopes., Typescript with corrections. 533pp. In two parts, both in black, plastic binders. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Part 1 of 2.
  - How Many Hopes. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Part 2 of 2.
  - Poor Richard. A palaopera., Typescript with extensive insertions and occasional notations and corrections. 194pp. In black, cardboard binder. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Some of the pages have colored sketches for set designs.
    (For musical score by Lucien Cailliet, see Correspondence, Box 25, in separate folder.)
  - The Pied Piper, by Barbara Lind [pseudonym]., 22pp. Typescript with corrections. In grey binder. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    This story with illustrations rewritten for Red Skelton.
    Also: Carbon copy (in same envelope).
  - The Pied Piper., In blue, paper binder. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    A synopsis composed primarily of pages of pencil sketches, with 22 numbered pages of typescript interspersed.
  - The Pied Piper of Hamlin, by Robert Browning, picturized by Hugo Ballin., 52pp. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Dummy of book with rough illustrations in color and no text.
  - Skylights, by William Croft [pseudonym]., Typescript (carbon) with corrections. 442pp. In wine, paper cover. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Skylights., 410pp. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Bound galleys with extensive holograph corrections. Note on first page reads: ...this story was accepted, as these galleys attest./The publisher failed in several ways...
  - The Brownstone House. By Antonio Gamio [pseudonym]., 341pp. Typescript with minor corrections. In brown covers. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Notation by Barbara Lind crossed out.
  - The Brownstone House., Typescript (carbon) with minor corrections. 341pp. In brown covers. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Also in envelope: Synopsis (Typescript, 4pp., in green, paper binder, 2 copies).
  - The Brownstone House. Pencil sketches and two pages of typescript (a synopsis)., 181pp. In black, spring binder. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pension Johnson., Holograph manuscript. Finished copy/October 22, 1952. Two pencil tablets in two envelopes. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Part 1 of 2, chapters 1-6.
  - Pension Johnson. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Part 2 of 2, chapters 7-14.
  - Pension Johnson., Typescript with corrections. 324pp. In two envelopes. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Part 1 of 2, pages 1-191.
  - Pension Johnson. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Part 2 of 2, pages 192-324.
  - Pension Johnson. Pacific Palisades, n.d.; Typescript (carbon) with corrections. 324pp. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Pension Johnson, an original play in three acts. Includes sketches of characters and sets., Typescript. 81pp. In blue, paper binder. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Pension Johnson, an original play in three acts. Sketches of characters and sets included., Typescript (carbon). 84pp. In black, paper binder. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - About Color., Typescript (carbon). 7 leaves. In folder. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Commando, or, The Ghost of John Grange., Typescript with corrections. 13pp. In folder. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cydalise, Heart of the King., 19pp. In yellow, paper binder with original sketch on cover.; Typescript. This outline was written for pictures [musical]. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - I'll Be Damned., Original copy. Typescript with occasional corrections. 480pp. Two, black, plastic binders in two envelopes. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Hugo Ballin's memoirs. Part 1 of 2, pages 1-239.
  - I'll Be Damned. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Part 2 of 2, pages 240-480.
  - I'll Be Damned., Typescript (carbon) with some corrections. 480pp. In two envelopes. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Part 1 of 2, pages 1-253.
  - I'll Be Damned. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Part 2 of 2, pages 254-480.
  - The Pedlar., Typescript with minor corrections. Also, color illustration of the Pedlar. 23pp. In folder. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Woman at the Door, by R. Cleaden [pseudonym]. Synopsis., Typescript, 13pp. In blue, paper cover. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Woman at the Door, by R. Cleaden [pseudonym]. Published in Hollywood, Authors Publishing Company, 1925.; Typescript (carbon). 13pp. 2 copies. In folder. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - The Enchanted Canyon Fairy Story, by Homer H. Mitten. Published by the Williams Press, San Francisco, 1933.; Typescript with corrections and some printer's notations, 314pp. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Meal Ticket and Applesauce, by Barbara Lind [pseudonym]., Typescript (carbon) with occasional corrections. 397pp. In black, spring binder. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Mountain of Venus, by Barbara Lind [pseudonym]., Typescript with corrections. 248pp. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Mountain of Venus. Sketches of the characters., 27 leaves. In black, spring binder. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    First leaf has holograph note: not to be used if published.
  - The Long Stairs., Typescript (carbon). Photostats of sketches on outside and inside of front cover. 533pp. In pressboard cover. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - The First Fifty Years Are the Hardest., Typescript (carbon). 283pp. In brown, paper binding. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - My Pilgrimage., Typescript (carbon) with extensive holograph notes and corrections. 147pp. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Help: a Farce, By a Lady in Waiting., Typescript with extensive holograph corrections. 31pp. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Paradise Road, by Barbara Lind [pseudonym]., Typescript, with corrections. 3pp. In folder. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Poison for Rats: an Episode in the Mulde Valley., Typescript with extensive holograph corrections and additions. 5pp. In folder. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Stranger, by Brother Joseph [pseudonym]., Typescript with numerous holograph corrections. 226pp. In black, spring binder. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    First few leaves have pencil sketches of the characters.
  - The Stranger., Typescript (carbon) with extensive holograph corrections. 226pp. In black, spring binder. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - The Stranger, by Barbara Lind [pseudonym]., Typescript. 4pp. In folder. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The Stranger., Typescript with some corrections. 5pp. In folder. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - The Acme of Appreciation. Publisher's letter of rejection attached., Typescript. 5pp. In folder. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - The Aftermath, by R. Cleaden [pseudonym]., Typescript (carbon). 26pp. In folder. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Alone., Typescript. 9pp. Also: 2nd copy (carbon). In folder. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - The Broken Cornice., Typescript with corrections. 7pp. In folder. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Expatriates. (written for pictures)., Typescript. 289pp. In two envelopes. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Expatriates. (written for pictures). (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Grains of Paradise, by Psyche Lind [pseudonym]., Typescript (carbon). 32pp. In folder.; Submitted for George Washington Carver Memorial Award, letter attached. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Honor and Obey., Typescript (carbon) with extensive corrections. 8pp. In folder. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - I Saw the Ghost of Amasa Abraham., Typescript. 7pp. In folder. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Just for Tonight, by R. Cleaden [pseudonym]., Typescript. 9pp. In folder. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Mr. Claus Goes Shopping: a Christmas Story for Children of All Ages., Typescript. 134pp. In black, spring binder. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - We'll Meet Again., Typescript (carbon). 442pp. In two envelopes. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - We'll Meet Again., Typescript (carbon). 442pp. In two envelopes. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Melissa of Arezzo. A play in 5 acts. Also: Synopsis., Typescript with some corrections. 107pp. Synopsis: 3pp., typescript. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, short manuscripts. Many incomplete., 14 items in an envelope. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (1 of 2)., In an envelope. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (2 of 2)., In an envelope. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - The American Diary, 1892. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Personal calendar and diary.
  - The American Diary, 1894. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Notes [notebook]., 1896. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Diary of Ballin's July 1896 voyage to Europe with his mother.
  - The Broken Toy. New York: W.J. Watt & Company, 1924. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Woman at the Door. Hollywood: Authors Publishing Company, 1925. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Stigma. New York: Macaulay, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Screen Acting, by Inez and Helen Klumph. New York: Falk, 1922. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    (Reference to Mabel Ballin on p. 145.)
  - Dolce Far Niente. Los Angeles: Suttonhouse, 1933.; 2 autographed and hand-numbered first editions. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Copy number 2 of 250. Note opposite title page reads: To Mabel Ballin / Xmas - 1932.
  - Dolce Far Niente. Los Angeles: Suttonhouse, 1933. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Copy number 108 of 250.
  - Mural Paintings by Hugo Ballin. New York: Privately printed, 1913. (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
    2 copies.